Support Admin Watch on kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
دعم الإدارة، شاهد على kissasia.cam أو kisskh.org
=The Architect=
=المهندس المعماري=
=Episode 29= (We only seek the truth)
=الحلقة 29= (نحن نبحث فقط عن الحقيقة)
I hereby accuse Xiao Huaijin of two crimes.
بموجب هذا أتهم شياو هوايجين بارتكاب جريمتين.
First,
أولاً،
Xiao Huaijin forged Shen Wenyuan's notes
قام Xiao Huaijin بتزوير ملاحظات Shen Wenyuan
to frame the Shen family,
لتلفيق تهمة لعائلة شين،
and illegally trafficked iron ore.
وخام الحديد المهرب بشكل غير قانوني.
Second,
ثانية،
Xiao Huaijin smuggled iron ore out of the country
قام شياو هوايجين بتهريب خام الحديد خارج البلاد
and sold it to the enemy general Jin Pulu,
وباعها للجنرال العدو جين بولو،
so he could amass troops and forge weapons.
حتى يتمكن من حشد القوات وصنع الأسلحة.
Pei Yu.
باي يو.
You colluded with unruly commoners to deceive me.
لقد تواطأت مع عامة الناس المتمردين لخداعي.
My death means nothing,
موتي لا يعني شيئاً،
but the Shen family's wrongful case has yet to be cleared.
لكن قضية عائلة شين الظالمة لم يتم البت فيها بعد.
Tens of thousands of workers of Shen Shipping
عشرات الآلاف من عمال شركة شين للشحن
are crying out for justice,
يطالبون بالعدالة،
trapped in endless suffering.
محاصرون في معاناة لا تنتهي.
I cling to this last breath
أتشبث بهذه الأنفاس الأخيرة
only to seek justice for them.
فقط سعياً لتحقيق العدالة لهم.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
In the Shen family case,
في قضية عائلة شين،
the culprit not only sought to frame the Shen family,
لم يكتفِ الجاني بالسعي إلى تلفيق التهمة لعائلة شين،
but also to use it to conceal
ولكن أيضًا لاستخدامه للإخفاء
his treacherous ambition and treason.
طموحه الغادر وخيانته.
If my death
إذا مت
caneradicate traitors
القضاء على الخونة
and preserve the peace of the state,
والحفاظ على سلامة الدولة،
then I am willing to sacrifice myself.
إذن فأنا على استعداد للتضحية بنفسي.
- Governor Pei.
- الحاكم باي.
The Prince Duan case
قضية الأمير دوان
deserves condemnation.
يستحق الإدانة.
I ask all of you to join me
أطلب منكم جميعاً الانضمام إليّ
in setting the truth right across the realm,
في سبيل وضع الحقيقة في جميع أنحاء المملكة،
for the sake of the world and the people.
من أجل العالم والناس.
Prince Duan colluded with the enemy.
تواطأ الأمير دوان مع العدو.
He must be condemned.
يجب إدانته.
My lords.
سادتي.
Whoever helps His Majesty set the truth right across the realm
كل من يساعد جلالته في نشر الحق في جميع أنحاء المملكة
will earn merit for generations to come.
سيكسب ذلك ثواباً للأجيال القادمة.
Merit for generations to come.
فضلٌ للأجيال القادمة.
My lords.
سادتي.
I, Pei, pay my respects to you all.
أنا، باي، أقدم لكم جميعاً احترامي وتقديري.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
When the people live in peace,
عندما يعيش الناس في سلام،
the realm is at peace.
المملكة تنعم بالسلام.
What is more,
علاوة على ذلك،
this matter concerns
هذا الأمر يثير القلق
relations between two states.
العلاقات بين دولتين.
In my humble view,
في رأيي المتواضع،
it must be handled
يجب التعامل مع الأمر
with the utmost caution.
بأقصى درجات الحذر.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
The Shen case has spread widely among the people
انتشرت قضية شين على نطاق واسع بين الناس
and drawn intense attention across the capital.
وقد حظي باهتمام كبير في جميع أنحاء العاصمة.
If there is no resolution,
إذا لم يتم التوصل إلى حل،
or if the outcome is unjust,
أو إذا كانت النتيجة غير عادلة،
it may
قد
undermine the authority of the court.
تقويض سلطة المحكمة.
- We beg Your Majesty to think carefully.
نرجو من جلالتكم التفكير ملياً .
(It seems)
(يبدو)
(the moment has come.)
(لقد حانت اللحظة.)
Fine.
بخير.
Very well.
جيد جدا.
You guys
يا رفاق
are forcing me to do this!
إنهم يجبرونني على فعل هذا!
Tell me!
أخبرني!
Just how much have you all received from the Shen family?
كم تلقيتم جميعاً من عائلة شين؟
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
The Shen family's loyalty to the court
ولاء عائلة شين للبلاط
needs no vouching.
لا يحتاج إلى تزكية.
In the eleventh year of the late emperor's Dazhen reign,
في السنة الحادية عشرة من حكم الإمبراطور الراحل دازين،
foreign forces invaded Daliang.
غزت القوات الأجنبية مدينة داليانغ.
The Shen family sold off their assets
باعت عائلة شين ممتلكاتها
to raise two million dan of military grain for the court.
لجمع مليوني دان من الحبوب العسكرية للمحكمة.
In the twenty-first year of Dazhen,
في السنة الحادية والعشرين من عهد دازين،
rebels rose up in the southeast.
ثار المتمردون في الجنوب الشرقي.
The Shen family once again
عائلة شين مرة أخرى
raised twenty million taels in military funds.
تم جمع عشرين مليون تيل كتمويل عسكري.
In the fifth year of the current reign,
في السنة الخامسة من الحكم الحالي،
there was a drought in the northwest.
كان هناك جفاف في الشمال الغربي.
In the eighth year, floods ravaged the south.
وفي السنة الثامنة، اجتاحت الفيضانات الجنوب.
Every act of the Shen family's loyalty to the court
كل عمل من أعمال ولاء عائلة شين للبلاط
is clearly
من الواضح
recorded by the Ministry of Revenue.
مسجلة لدى وزارة الإيرادات.
You claim you obtained
تدعي أنك حصلت
evidence of Xiao Huaijin colluding with the enemy.
دليل على تواطؤ شياو هوايجين مع العدو.
Jin Pulu is a treacherous official of an enemy state.
جين بولو مسؤول خائن في دولة معادية.
How did you
كيف فعلت ذلك؟
manage to make contact with him?
هل تمكنت من التواصل معه؟
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
I infiltrated Jin Pulu's secret military camp
لقد تسللت إلى المعسكر العسكري السري لجين بولو
and discovered tens of thousands of troops stationed there,
واكتشفت عشرات الآلاف من القوات المتمركزة هناك،
along with workshops forging weapons.
إلى جانب ورش تصنيع الأسلحة.
The iron ore they used
خام الحديد الذي استخدموه
came from Xiao Huaijin's trafficking.
جاء ذلك من تجارة شياو هوايجين.
As Governor of Daliang,
بصفته حاكم داليانغ،
you managed to enter
لقد تمكنت من الدخول
the secret camp of a traitorous enemy general.
المعسكر السري لجنرال عدو خائن.
Pei Yu.
باي يو.
Are you not pointing fingers to cover your own crime?
ألا تقوم بتوجيه أصابع الاتهام للتغطية على جريمتك؟
What troubles Your Majesty
ما الذي يزعج جلالتكم
is nothing more than my loyalty.
ليس الأمر سوى ولائي.
To prove it, I am willing to relinquish my post as Governor,
ولإثبات ذلك، فأنا على استعداد للتخلي عن منصبي كحاكم.
and surrender command of the Qilin Guards,
والتخلي عن قيادة حرس الكيلين،
to accept Your Majesty's judgment.
قبول حكم جلالتكم.
Fine.
بخير.
You all think
جميعكم تعتقدون
this is enough to force my hand?
هل هذا كافٍ لإجباري على اتخاذ قرار؟
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
- All we ask
كل ما نطلبه - كل ما نطلبه
- is the truth.
- هي الحقيقة.
- We need Your Majesty's wise judgment.
- نحن بحاجة إلى حكمة جلالتكم.
Very well.
جيد جدا.
I will order
سأطلب
the Court of Judicial Review to investigate thoroughly.
المحكمة القضائية للمراجعة القضائية للتحقيق بشكل شامل.
If the allegations are proven true, the Prince Duan's Residence
إذا ثبتت صحة هذه الادعاءات، فإن مقر إقامة الأمير دوان
shall be dealt with according to the law.
سيتم التعامل معها وفقاً للقانون.
I am weary.
أنا متعب.
You may all withdraw.
يمكنكم جميعاً الانسحاب.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
Since Prince Duan's Residence has been proven to be guilty,
وبما أن إدانة مقر إقامة الأمير دوان قد ثبتت،
the Shen case
قضية شين
should also be retried to restore faith among the people.
ينبغي أيضاً إعادة المحاولة لاستعادة الثقة بين الناس.
The guilt of the Prince Duan's Residence
ذنب مقر إقامة الأمير دوان
does not mean the Shen family's innocence.
لا يعني ذلك براءة عائلة شين.
The Shen case was settled long ago.
تمت تسوية قضية شين منذ زمن طويل.
This matter
هذه المسألة
is not to be mentioned again.
لا ينبغي ذكر ذلك مرة أخرى.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
Dozens of lives from the Shen family
عشرات الأرواح من عائلة شين
were slaughtered in a single night.
تم ذبحهم في ليلة واحدة.
Men, women, young and old, none were spared.
لم ينجُ أحد ، رجالاً ونساءً، صغاراً وكباراً .
Those who hear of it are horrified,
يصاب من يسمع بذلك بالرعب.
those who speak of it turn pale.
أولئك الذين يتحدثون عنه يشحب وجههم.
Now that the evidence lies before us,
والآن وقد أصبحت الأدلة أمامنا،
why does Your Majesty choose to ignore their injustice?
لماذا يختار جلالتكم تجاهل الظلم الذي لحق بهم؟
Why you...
لماذا أنت...
(To My Father) Your Majesty!
(إلى والدي) جلالتك!
Do you really
هل أنت حقاً
want Li Wan'er's tragedy to happen all over again?
هل تريد أن تتكرر مأساة لي وان إير من جديد؟
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
(To My Father)
(إلى والدي)
(Father, I don't know whether I should feel happiness or irony.)
(يا أبي، لا أعرف ما إذا كان عليّ أن أشعر بالسعادة أم بالسخرية.)
(Father.)
(أب.)
(To call you my father again,)
(لأناديك أبي مرة أخرى،)
(I don't know whether I should feel happiness)
(لا أعرف ما إذا كان ينبغي عليّ أن أشعر بالسعادة)
(or irony.)
(أو من باب المفارقة).
(You granted my father)
(لقد منحت والدي)
(the posthumous title Duke Zhongguo.)
(اللقب بعد وفاته الدوق تشونغ قوه.)
(You bestowed upon me the honor and wealth of a Princess.)
(لقد منحتني شرف وثروة أميرة.)
(Only now do I finally understand.)
(أفهم الآن فقط.)
(The fine silks I wear)
(الحرير الفاخر الذي أرتديه)
(and the brilliant future beneath my feet)
(والمستقبل المشرق الذي ينتظرني)
(were paid for with my father's bones)
(تم دفع ثمنها بعظام والدي)
(and the blood of the Li Army's soldiers.)
(ودماء جنود جيش لي).
(I was nothing more than a tool you used)
(لم أكن أكثر من مجرد أداة استخدمتها)
(to balance the court and control the Li Army.)
(لتحقيق التوازن في البلاط والسيطرة على جيش لي.)
(I should have demanded justice from Heaven.)
(كان ينبغي عليّ أن أطالب بالعدالة من السماء.)
(I should have made you pay for my father's life.)
(كان ينبغي أن أجعلك تدفع ثمن حياة والدي.)
(But what I thought of most)
(لكن هذا ما فكرت فيه أكثر)
(was all these years)
(كان ذلك طوال هذه السنوات)
(of unmatched happiness)
(من السعادة التي لا مثيل لها)
(you gave me.)
(أعطيتني إياه.)
(If I do not avenge my father,)
(إذا لم أنتقم لأبي،)
(I am unworthy to be a human being.)
(أنا لا أستحق أن أكون إنسانًا.)
(Killing you)
(أقتلك)
(is beyond my courage.)
(هذا يتجاوز شجاعتي.)
(What lies before me)
(ما ينتظرني)
(is only one path.)
(هذا مسار واحد فقط.)
(I am guilty.)
(أنا مذنب.)
(When the Shen family fell into ruin,)
(عندما انهارت عائلة شين،)
(I betrayed sisterhood and struck them while they were down.)
(لقد خنتُ أخواتي وضربتهن وهن في أضعف حالاتهن.)
(Since then, my dreams have never known peace.)
(منذ ذلك الحين، لم تعرف أحلامي السلام قط.)
(Father, have you ever, in the still of the night,)
(يا أبي، هل سبق لك أن، في سكون الليل،)
(seen those from the past in your dreams)
(هل رأيتَ أشخاصًا من الماضي في أحلامك؟)
(asking you for an answer?)
(هل تطلب منك إجابة؟)
(Let it go, Father.)
(دع الأمر يمر يا أبي.)
(Don't let the bond between ruler and subject,)
(لا تدع الرابطة بين الحاكم والمحكوم تضعف)
(blood ties between family,)
(روابط الدم بين أفراد الأسرة)
(and the hearts of the people)
(وقلوب الناس)
(be destroyed by baseless suspicion.)
(يُدمر بسبب شكوك لا أساس لها.)
Wan'er.
وانير.
How could you be so foolish?
كيف لك أن تكون بهذا الغباء؟
We have been father and daughter for so many years.
لقد كنا أباً وابنة لسنوات عديدة.
In my heart,
في قلبي،
you are never just a tool.
أنت لست مجرد أداة.
Silly child.
طفل ساذج.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
I have one more item to present.
لديّ عنصر آخر لأعرضه.
This was Wan'er's most treasured possession.
كان هذا أغلى ما يملكه وانير .
She never let it out of her sight.
لم تدعها تغيب عن ناظريها أبداً.
It was a gift you personally gave her
لقد كانت هدية قدمتها لها شخصياً
on the day the Princess came of age.
في اليوم الذي بلغت فيه الأميرة سن الرشد.
In the Princess's heart,
في قلب الأميرة،
even with resentment,
حتى مع وجود الاستياء،
she could never bring herself to blame Your Majesty.
لم تستطع أبداً أن تلوم جلالتكم.
Because to her, you are both her sovereign and her father,
لأنك بالنسبة لها سيدها وأبوها في آن واحد،
and the one the people of the realm rely on.
والذي يعتمد عليه أهل المملكة.
Your Majesty, if you will not seek justice for the Shen family,
يا صاحب الجلالة، إن لم تسعوا لتحقيق العدالة لعائلة شين،
then who possibly can?
إذن من يستطيع فعل ذلك؟
I am
أنا أكون
the sovereign father of the people of Daliang,
الأب الحاكم لشعب داليانغ،
and their only pillar of support.
وعمود دعمهم الوحيد.
The imperial household knows no affection.
لا تعرف العائلة الإمبراطورية أي عاطفة.
An emperor is forever prone to suspicion.
الإمبراطور عرضة للشك دائماً.
He is willing to sacrifice anyone.
إنه مستعد للتضحية بأي شخص.
Now,
الآن،
Pei Yu and the others have secured irrefutable proof.
لقد حصل باي يو والآخرون على دليل قاطع لا يمكن دحضه.
I will inevitably meet the same end as General Li.
سألقى حتماً نفس مصير الجنرال لي.
Since that is the case,
وبما أن الأمر كذلك،
rather than waiting to be slaughtered,
بدلاً من انتظار الذبح،
I might as well gamble everything.
ربما من الأفضل أن أغامر بكل شيء.
Your Highness is wise.
سموكم حكيم.
When I departed,
عندما غادرت،
General Jin instructed me
أصدر الجنرال جين تعليماته لي
to follow Prince Duan's commands
اتباع أوامر الأمير دوان
and ensure Prince Duan's success in the campaign.
وضمان نجاح الأمير دوان في الحملة.
Brothers!
يا إخوة!
The palace gates have been forced open.
تم فتح أبواب القصر بالقوة.
Whoever helps me
كل من يساعدني
take the darned emperor's head
اقطع رأس الإمبراطور اللعين
will be remembered as a founding hero of my dynasty.
سيُذكر كبطل مؤسس لسلالتي.
From this day on, you'll rise to the highest ranks,
ابتداءً من هذا اليوم، ستترقى إلى أعلى المراتب،
be granted lands and titles, nothing will be withheld.
سيتم منحهم الأراضي والسندات، ولن يتم حجب أي شيء.
- Prince Duan is wise!
- الأمير دوان حكيم!
Bad news! Prince Duan has rebelled!
خبر سيء! لقد تمرد الأمير دوان!
Protect the Emperor!
احموا الإمبراطور!
Your Majesty, this is...
جلالتكم، هذا...
We're in the inner palace.
نحن في القصر الداخلي.
How could rebels breach it?
كيف يمكن للمتمردين اختراقه؟
Your Majesty, this must be Xiao Huaijin.
يا صاحب الجلالة، لا بد أن هذا هو شياو هوايجين.
He's been plotting this.
لقد كان يخطط لهذا.
He used Your Majesty's birthday banquet to launch his revolt.
استغل مأدبة عيد ميلاد جلالتكم لإطلاق تمرده.
I will
أنا سوف
immediately mobilize the Qilin Guards
حشد حراس الكيلين على الفور
to subdue the rebels.
لإخضاع المتمردين.
I urge Your Majesty
أناشد جلالتكم
to leave the palace through the secret passage.
مغادرة القصر عبر الممر السري.
Your Majesty,
جلالتك،
the Shen family has
عائلة شين لديها
a hidden chamber
غرفة مخفية
that is impossible to find.
من المستحيل العثور على ذلك.
I'll take Your Majesty there at once.
سآخذ جلالتكم إلى هناك على الفور.
(Weitian Hall)
(قاعة ويتيان)
Darned emperor!
يا له من إمبراطور ملعون!
Come out and meet your death!
اخرج وواجه موتك!
Prince Duan.
الأمير دوان.
They fled to the Shen residence.
فرّوا إلى منزل عائلة شين.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
This secret chamber
هذه الغرفة السرية
is concealed within the rockery.
مخفي داخل الحديقة الصخرية.
It is
إنها
reinforced with black iron stone,
مُدعّم بحجر حديدي أسود،
impervious to attacks.
منيع ضد الهجمات.
Your Majesty may take refuge here.
قد يلجأ جلالتكم إلى هنا.
(End of Episode)
(نهاية الحلقة)
I promise you,
أعدك،
the Shen family's case will be retried.
ستتم إعادة محاكمة قضية عائلة شين.
And now you would still
والآن ما زلت ستفعل
cause your own sister's death for his sake?
هل تتسبب في موت أختك من أجله؟
♪Loneliness♪
الشعور بالوحدة
♪How do I cross it?♪
كيف أعبرها؟
♪Whom have I ever failed♪
من خذلتُ في حياتي؟
♪Incense burns through a few sticks♪
يحرق البخور بضع أعواد فقط؟
♪Can the rest of my life be redeemed?♪
هل يمكن إصلاح ما تبقى من حياتي؟
♪The flowing years pass through desolation♪
تمر السنين المتدفقة عبر الخراب.
♪Unwilling to forgive past mistakes♪
غير راغب في مسامحة أخطاء الماضي؟
♪Blaming myself for not protecting♪
ألوم نفسي لعدم حمايتي لنفسي.
♪Our vows as I should have♪
عهودنا كما ينبغي لي أن أفعل.
♪Sorrow♪
؟؟؟حزن؟؟؟
♪Counting it carefully♪
???أحصيها بعناية؟
♪Who stayed by my side through hardship♪
من بقي بجانبي في الشدائد؟
♪There will eventually be a pure land♪
سيأتي يومٌ تكون فيه أرضٌ طاهرة.
♪Where all karmic burden is cast away♪
حيث يتم التخلص من كل عبء كارمي
♪Not until worldly splendor fades♪
لن يحدث ذلك إلا بعد أن يزول بريق الدنيا.
♪Can one understand what cuts to the bone♪
هل يمكن للمرء أن يفهم ما الذي يقطع العظم؟
♪At dusk, with white hair♪
عند الغسق، بشعر أبيض؟
♪I still cannot fathom destiny♪
ما زلتُ عاجزاً عن فهم القدر.
♪After countless struggles across the waters♪
بعد صراعات لا حصر لها عبر المياه
♪At last the lotus heart awakens♪
أخيرًا يستيقظ قلب اللوتس!
♪Drifting across three lifetimes♪
???الانجراف عبر ثلاث حيوات؟
♪Just to wait for your once-in-a-thousand-years glance♪
مجرد انتظار لنظرتك التي لا تتكرر إلا مرة كل ألف عام؟
♪The distant mountains fade along the path home♪
تتلاشى الجبال البعيدة على طول الطريق المؤدي إلى المنزل.
♪I walk with you through morning bells and evening drums♪
أسير معك عبر أجراس الصباح وطبول المساء.
♪Our story lies in the mountains♪
قصتنا تكمن في الجبال
♪Like an ink-washed immortal painting♪
???مثل لوحة خالدة مغسولة بالحبر؟؟؟
♪Where blossoms fall♪
أين تتساقط الأزهار؟
♪I'm glad the fragrance in our hearts stays the same♪
أنا سعيد لأن العطر في قلوبنا يبقى كما هو.
♪Youth slips away♪
يتلاشى الشباب تدريجياً
♪Just to wait for your once-in-a-thousand-years glance♪
مجرد انتظار لنظرتك التي لا تتكرر إلا مرة كل ألف عام؟
♪Dreams wander back to the old road where we met♪
تعود الأحلام إلى الطريق القديم حيث التقينا.
♪Watching you gently play the zither♪
أشاهدك وأنت تعزف على آلة الزيثارة برفق.
♪Time rests upon the strings♪
يستقر الزمن على الأوتار.
♪Waiting for someone to brew a pot of tea♪
أنتظر أن يقوم أحدهم بتحضير إبريق شاي؟